mapinc.org 2017-12-11

# DrugSense/Media Awareness Project Inc. Privacy Policy | DrugSense

Effective as of July 27, 2010. 

1 **INTRODUCTION**

We take the privacy of members of, and visitors to, the http://www.mapinc.org/, http://www.drugpolicycentral.com/ and http://www.drugsense.org/ websites (the “Service”) very seriously. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more about how the Media Awareness Project Inc. (“MAP,” “we,” our,” or “us”) treats information, including personally identifiable information, in connection with the Service. We provide this Privacy Policy because visitors to our websites have a right to know what information we collect, how it is protected and used, and the circumstances under which it may be disclosed. If you have comments, suggestions, questions, or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us via email at or by post at: 

    DrugSense,
    14252 Culver Drive #328,
    Irvine, CA
    92604-0326.

_Online Privacy Standards_. We follow the principles supported by the Federal Trade Commission’s Fair Information Practices Principles, currently available at <http://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy3/fairinfo.shtm>. 

_What This Policy Covers_. This policy covers the ways in which MAP treats information, including personally identifiable information, which we obtain when you use our Service. We regard personally identifiable information as information that someone can use to identify or contact you in person, such as your real name, telephone number, birth date, email address, or physical mailing address. Neither the technical information associated with your access to the Service – such as your internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), site entry/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data – nor information that we use internally to identify you as a user in our system is considered personally identifiable information.

_What This Policy Does Not Cover_. This policy does not cover the privacy practices of third parties that we do not own or control. In addition, we may provide links to other services and on occasion to other sites that may interest you. All of these sites operate independently of MAP and each has its own privacy and security practices. For your best on-line experience, we encourage you to review each website’s privacy and security policies before submitting any personal information to that website. 

2 **HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION**

**Information You Provide**

_When You Subscribe_ **.** When you choose to subscribe to our email newsletter, you will be asked to provide a valid email address.

_When You Upload Content_ **.** When you chose to upload content to the Service, you will be asked to provide a valid email address.

_When You Email Content_. The Service makes it possible for you email content located on the server to third parties and to yourself. When you choose to email content using this feature, you will be asked to provide a valid email address.

_When You Donate_. When you choose to donate to MAP, you will be asked to provide information sufficient to complete your donation (e.g., your credit card information, billing address, etc.), along with a valid email address.

**Information We Do Not Collect From Any Users**

_Children_ . As explained further in our Terms of Use (available at [http://www.drugsense.org/terms_of_use](http://www.drugsense.org./terms_of_use)), you must be 18 years of age or older – or, if you are under the age of majority in your jurisdiction, have the consent of your parent or guardian – to use the Service. Therefore, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from or about children. In accordance with Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), MAP will never knowingly solicit, nor will we accept, personally identifiable information from visitors known to be under thirteen (13) years of age. If you believe that we have information from or about anyone under 13 years of age, please notify us by email at , or write to our Privacy Officer at the address noted above.

**Information We Track**

_Log Files_. Similar to many websites and internet services, we gather certain anonymous, non-personal information automatically and store it in web server log files. This information includes internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), site entry/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data. We use this information to improve our site, analyze trends, administer the site, and gather aggregate information about our user base as a whole. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of services or users from which individual user identities have been removed, and therefore does not include your personally identifiable information.

_Cookies_. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. It can also help us understand how our site visitors arrive at our site and what pages they view during their visit. Similar to many websites, the Service stores an encrypted cookie on your computer so we can remember you when you come back without requiring you to log in each time. Cookies also allow us to track and understand the interests of our visitors and to enhance the overall experience on our Service. Cookies used by MAP do not include your personally identifiable information

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can set your web browser software to disable them. To do so, please refer to the help section of your specific browser for more information on how to manage or disable cookies. Please note that your browser must be configured to accept cookies to use some components of the Service.

3 **HOW WE USE INFORMATION**

**MAP Communications**

We use emails and/or prominent notifications on our website as our primary means to inform our users of important Service announcements.

_Email Subscription Services_. We use the email address you provide us to deliver information from MAP – and other like-minded entities – to you. These communications are purely optional, and each such communication will contain a prominent “unsubscribe” link to allow you to opt out of such communications going forward. There are also forms online where you can opt out of receiving future emails located at <http://www.drugsense.org/lists/> and <http://www.mapinc.org/lists/>. 

**On Our Website**

_When Sharing Content_. When you chose to share content using the Service, you will be asked to provide your first and last name and email address. This information will appear online in connection with the content you have shared. Please do not include any personally identifiable information which you choose not to share in any field that will accompany the content. 

_Site Statistics_. As noted above, we use information collected from our web log files to calculate and publish anonymous, non-personal, aggregate statistics that we believe our users are interested in viewing. For example, we may track and publish the total number of users who have viewed a particular piece of published content. We publish this data in aggregate form only, and do not tie it to any personally identifiable information.

_When You Donate_. When you donate to MAP, we store the information you provide to contact you later regarding MAP and the Service.

**For Internal Reporting and Analysis**

As noted above, we use information gathered from log files and cookies to improve our site, analyze trends, administer the site, track the movement of users around the site, and to gather aggregate information about our user base as a whole. We do not tie this data to personally identifiable information.

4 **HOW WE SHARE AND DISCLOSE INFORMATION**

**With Third-Parties**

_Sharing, Renting, and Selling Information We Collect_. We will neither rent nor sell your personally identifiable information to anyone. We may share your personally identifiable information, including your email address, with like-minded entities for the purpose of furthering the mission of MAP to inform the public. Occasionally we also share anonymous, non-personal, aggregate information about our user base with third parties, and we may publish these aggregate usage statistics on our website for the interest of our users. We do not tie this aggregate usage data to the personally identifiable information of any person. 

_Linked Services_. In some cases, we allow you to access or link to other web services through our website. We make it easy for you to determine when you are accessing or linking to these other web services through our website. In all of these cases, those sites may choose to collect your personal information as they deem appropriate. As noted above, we are not responsible for or in control of how third parties collect, use, or disclose your information obtained through these linked services. We encourage you to be aware when you are using these third party services and, for your best on-line experience, we encourage you to review their policies before submitting any personal information to them.

**As Necessary In Certain Legal Circumstances**

_Legal Requirements_. We reserve the right to disclose your information, including personally identifiable information, when we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of such information is necessary to (a) comply with any law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce these Terms of Use, including investigation of potential violations of these Terms of Use, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of MAP, its users, or the public as required or permitted by law.

_Acquisition_. If MAP becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, including bankruptcy, our assets, including user information, may be transferred to a third party. At that time, your user information may become subject to that third party’s privacy policy. Before we transfer your user information, we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on our site.

5 **HOW WE KEEP INFORMATION SECURE**

_Security of Account Information_. MAP employs standard commercial security measures to maintain and protect the safety and confidentiality of your personal information.

6 **UPDATES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

From time to time we will review, and may make changes to, our privacy policy. When we do so, we will either notify you by email or by placing a prominent notice on the Service. The most recent version of our Privacy Policy is always available at http://www.drugsense.org/privacy/
